It was 1973, and the climate was changing.
The Ice Storm is a drama film directed by Ang Lee.
In the weekend after thanksgiving 1973 the Hood
family is skidding out of control.
Then an ice storm hits, the worst in a century.
Ben Hood, played by Kevin Kline.
Elena Hood, played by Joan Allen.
Janey Carver, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Jim Carver, played by Jamey Sheridan.
Wendy Hood, played by Christina Ricci.
Paul Hood, played by Tobey Maguire.
The Ice Storm is a 1997 American drama film directed by Ang Lee and written by
James Schamus adapting the 1994 novel The Ice Storm by Rick Moody.
During Thanksgiving in 1973, two neighboring suburban families seek escape from
their emotional emptiness through infidelity and self-indulgence.
The film stars Kevin Kline, Joan Allen, Tobey Maguire, Christina Ricci, Elijah Wood,
Katie Holmes, Glenn Fitzgerald, Jamey Sheridan, and Sigourney Weaver.
The film was produced by Fox Searchlight Pictures on a budget of $18 million.
The film premiered on May 12, 1997, at the 1997 Cannes Film Festival, where
Schamus won the Cannes Film Festival Award for Best Screenplay.
Fox Searchlight gave the film a limited theatrical release
in the United States on September 27, 1997.
It grossed $8 million in the U.S., and it grossed $8 million
outside the US for a worldwide total of $16 million.
Among other accolades, Weaver won the BAFTA Award for
Best Actress in a Supporting Role.
The film explores themes of infidelity, based on novel or
book, 1970s, thanksgiving, dysfunctional family.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.